어지러운 전국 시대.
It is the turbulent Sengoku period.
카라쿠리인이 사는 지팡구국에서는 군웅할거하여 밤낮으로 접전이 계속되고
Warlords keep on fighting day and night over
Jipangu State, where Karakuri people live.
카라쿠리 무예가들도 승리와 영광을 꿈꾸며 맹렬히 싸우고 있었다.
Karakuri martial artists were sharpening their swords, dreaming of victory and honor.
그리고 지금, 카라쿠리 무예가 제일을 꿈꾸는 터무니없는 영웅이 탄생했다!
And now, a wild hero has arrived, seeking to be the number one Karakuri martial artist!
무사시 등장이오!
Musashi is here-dasu!
카라쿠리 검호전: 무사시 로드
Karakuri Kengouden
Musashi Road
(The Story of Karakuri Martial Artist: Road of Musashi)
사내는 언제나 세계 한가운데서
A man always dreams of the day
제일 강해질 날을
in the center of the world to become
아! 아! 꿈꿔라
AH! AH! the strongest
마음의 칼을 넓은 하늘로 번쩍 쳐들어
Raise the sword of your heart high to the wide sky
모험의 길의 막을 연다
Raise the curtain to the road of adventure
지팡구국을 떠도는 검호
A skilled swordsman roams on Jipangu State
그 이름은 카라쿠리인 무사시
His name is Musashi, a Karakuri man
격렬한 승부의 소리는
The sound of fierce duels
눈부신 인생
makes life dazzling
싸웠던 어제보다도 오늘 강해진다
Battles of yesterdays make you stronger today
무예! 이도류 무사시
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
내일은 빛난다
Tomorrow will be glorious
격렬한 승부의 소리는
The sound of fierce duels
눈부신 인생
makes life dazzling
싸우는 한껏 고요함과 함께
Fight the utmost with the stillness
무예! 이도류 무사시
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
미간이 반짝였다 무사시!!
His eyes shined! Musashi!
한조는 결국에 쥬베에게 계략을 들켜, 지팡구를 지배하려는 야망을 분명히 하고 달아났다.
Hanzo's evil plan was finally discovered by Jube, and he ran away after making clear of his ambition to rule over Jipangu.
오니히메는 무사시 일행을 덮쳐 센히메를 빼앗아 갔다.
Onihime attacked Musashi's group and took Senhime away.
그리고 센히메의 생명을 구해준다는 조건 하에 칼을 내려놓은 무사시와 코지로.
Musashi and Kojirō put their swords down in a condition of letting Senhime alive.
과연 센히메의 생명은!
Will Senhime survive?!
얼음도 녹이는
우정 파워이오
Ice-Melting
Power of Friendship
자! 칼은 내려뒀다! 약속을 지켜라!
See! We've put down our swords! Now keep the promise!
한조!
Hanzo!
약속 따위 얘들이나 하는 일을 언제까지 하고 있을 셈이냐, 무사시, 코지로?
Only kids make promises. Shouldn't you be old enough to stop being kids, Musashi, Kojirō?
천하를 노리는 이 한조, 방해하는 자는 전부 처치하지.
I, Hanzo, am after the domination of the whole globe. Whoever gets in my way will be gotten rid of.
더럽소! 그래도 무예가이오?!
That's dirty-dasu! You call yourself a martial artist-dasu?1
공교롭군. 난 닌자. 어떤 수를 써서라도 이기면 됐지.
How unfortunate. I am a ninja. If I can win, then it's good enough.
무사시! 코지로! 난 신경쓰지 말고 도망쳐!
Musashi! Kojirō! Forget about me and run for your lives!
더는 용서할 수 없소!
I won't forgive you anymore-dasu!
멍청한 자식.
What a fool.
살려줘!
Help!
지금 무사시와 우정으로 이어진 라이벌들이 서두른다.
The rivals yet friends of Musashi are hurrying.
과연 늦지 않을 수 있을 것인가!
Will they be able to make it in time?
무사시!
Musashi!
나, 틀렸소.
I won't make it-dasu.
무사시, 포기하지 마라!
Musashi, do not give up!
그걸 디딤판 삼아 올라가라!
Use those as stepping stones!
고맙소, 코지로!
Thank you, Kojirō!
가오!
I'm going-dasu!
오니히메! 승부를 보시오!
Onihime! Fight me-dasu!
웃기지 마라. 먹어라! 얼음벽!
How foolish! Take this! Ice Walls!
춥소...
It's so cold-dasu...
그런 걸로 날 쓰러뜨릴 쏘냐!
You aren't taking me down by that!
꽤 하는군, 코지로. 그럼 눈 콘크리트 작전.
That was pretty good, Kojirō. Then let me show you my Snow Concrete Strategy.
a vi ra hūṃ khaṃ, a vi ra hūṃ khaṃ...
아싸!
Yeah!
비참하군!
Pity me!
무사시! 코지로!
Musashi! Kojirō!
방해자는 처리했다. 이제 센히메만 남았군.
All the obstacles are gone. Only Senhime to go.
센히메 님!
Senhime!
내게 맡기쇼!
Leave it to me!
센히메 님!
Senhime!
쥬베! 모두!
Jube! Everyone!
네이놈, 쥬베! 또다시! 다들 살해해라!
Jube, you bastard! Again! Everyone, kill them!
센히메 님은 제가 받겠습니다!
I'll get Senhime!
우시와카, 팔쌍도약!
Ushiwaka! Double Eight Leap!
고마워, 우시와카! 괜찮아?
Thank you, Ushiwaka! Are you okay?
이제 안심하세요, 센히메 님.
You're safe now, Senhime.
우시와카 씨...
Mr. Ushiwaka...
좋은 라이벌을 악의 손에 죽게 두면 흥미롭지 않으니까요.
Leaving a good rival be dead to the hands of evil is not fun at all.
고맙소!
Thank you-dasu!
우시와카 씨! 센짱을 맡기오!
Mr. Ushiwaka! Take care of Sen-chan-dasu!
알겠습니다.
Got it.
무사시, 조심해.
Musashi, be careful!
오니히메, 이번엔 갚아주겠소!
Onihime! It's my turn to pay back-dasu!
센히메 님! 이 쪽으로!
Senhime! This way!
젠장! 이대로는 끝이 없군!
Damn! There's no end to this!
벤케이! 이걸 베어라!
Benkei! Cut this off!
뭐야?!
What?!
열렸군!
It worked!
한조! 이제 달아날 길은 없다! 각오해라!
Hanzo! You have nowhere to run now! Prepare yourself!
무슨. 네놈이야말로 원수를 갚아 주겠다!
Instead of that, you'll be paid for everything you did to me!
제기랄!
Damn!
멈춰라!
Stop!
아야! 젠장!
Ouch! Damn!
거기까지다!
That's as far as you go!
코지로! 지금까지 꼴불견이었던 주제에 입은 살았네!
Kojirō! You look pretty good, after being so disgraceful of yourself!
시끄럽다! 더는 못 달아날 테다!
Silence! You won't get away anymore!
과연 그럴까?
We'll see about that.
여기가 카라쿠리 요새라는 걸 잊었나 보군!
Did you forget that you're now at Karakuri Stronghold?
멈춰라!
Stop!
젠장!
Damn!
이번에야말로 끝장이다. 죽어라, 무사시!
You're actually going down this time! Die, Musashi!
코지로냐!
Kojirō?!
-이번엔 내가 상대해 주마!
-바라던 바다!
-I'll face you this time!
-Well then!
코지로! 네 칼이다!
Kojirō! Take your sword!
고맙다!
Thanks!
고맙소!
Thank you-dasu!
그럼 됐다! 이제 한조를 잡아라!
Now go get Hanzo!
무사시 님!
Mr. Musashi!
늦어서 미안하오!
Sorry for being late!
한조! 각오하시오!
Hanzo! Prepare yourself!
네이놈, 중과부적이다! 비겁하다!
You're outnumbering me, bastards! That's cowardly!
비겁? 어느 쪽 말이오!
Cowardly? Who do you mean by that-dasu?!
깨끗하게 단념해라, 한조!
Give it up if you have any honor!
시끄럽다! 지라이얀, 여긴 맡긴다!
Silence! Jiraiyan, I'm leaving this to you!
한조! 어디냐!
Hanzo! Where did you go?!
이 지라이얀이 상대해 주겠다!
I, Jiraiyan, will face you!
지라이얀! 소용없는 저항은 관두시오!
Jiraiyan! Give up your futile resistance-dasu!
우리 팀워크에 이길 수 있을거라 생각하느냐!
Do you think that you can win over our teamwork?!
한조 님은 우리 일족! 한 목숨 걸고 지키겠다!
Lord Hanzo belings to my clan! I will protect him risking my life!
그 각오는 훌륭하다! 그럼 이만 가거라!
That determination is respectable! Now disappear!
우정. 팀워크. 무예가에게 그런 게 있다면...
Friendship and teamwork. If a martial artist has those...
뭐, 뭣이오?
W- what is it-dasu?1
한조 님!
Lord Hanzo!
이렇게 된 바 한방에 처리해 주겠다. 각오해라!
I have no choice else than to take care of all of you at once. Prepare yourselves!
카라쿠리 요새에서의 결전은 위기 그리고 위기!
The decisive battle at Karakuri Stronghold is a series of crisis!
질풍노도의 후반을 기다려라!
Wait for the stormy latter half!
카라쿠리 검호전 무사시 로드
Karakuri Kengouden: Musashi Road
무사시 님! 빨리 이 쪽으로!
Mr. Musashi! This way, right now!
네이놈!
You bastard!
무사시 님!
Mr. Musashi!
지라이얀! 알아서 끝장내라!
Jiraiyan! You finish that!
삼
Three
이
Two
일
One
가
OK
이 정도의 실력을 갖고 있으면서 왜 악을 위해 일하나!
Why are you working for evil, with your level of skills?!
한조 님은 우리 일족. 그 은의를 위해! 그렇지만...
Lord Hanzo is my clan. For the obligation! But...
그 마음의 방황은 뭔가.
Why are you hesitating?
왜 그림자에서 살아가나. 우리와 같이 태양 아래에서 정정당당히 무예를 겨룰 생각은 없나!
Why do you live in shadows? Wouldn't you like to practice swordsmanship under the sun like us?
할 수 있다면 그러고 싶다! 그러나...
I'd be doing that if I could! But...
뭐야?!
What?!
오니히메!
Onihime!
왜 나를!
Why did you...
나도 인간. 그런 대로 빛 아래에서 코지로 님과 겨루어 보고 싶었다.
I am a human too. I wanted to have a fight with you, Kojirō, for once, under the light.
오니히메!
Onihime!
제기랄!
Damn!
거기까지다!
That's as far as you go!
포기하시오!
Give it up-dasu!
젠장!
Damn!
지라이얀! 뭘 어물쩌물대고 있냐!
Jiraiyan! You're being slow!
한조 님!
Lord Hanzo!
지라이얀! 저 둘을 저 세상에 안내해 줘라. 작별이다!
Jiraiyan! Guide them to the other world! Farewell!
누구냐!
Who's there?!
우정의 사슬의 위력을 어디 한번 보아라!
Feel the might of the chain of friendship!
바이켄!
Baiken!
바이켄! 와 주었소!
Baiken! You came for us-dasu!
무사시를 잃으면 지팡구 무예대회가 재미 없어지니까!
Without you, Musashi, Jipangu Martial Arts Competition won't be interesting as now!
이렇게나 큰 요새를 돌리려면 어딘가에 동력실이 있을 터.
There must be a power room, to operate a stronghold this big.
그걸 부수면 되는 거네.
So destroying that will do.
예쁘다!
It's so pretty!
센히메 님! 안 됩니다!
Senhime! No!
뭐야, 이거?!
What's this?!
위험했습니다.
That was close.
무서운 함정이 잔뜩이네.
It's full of scary traps...
센히메 님!
Senhime!
여긴...
Where are we?
둘이 사이좋게 꼬치나 되어라.
You two should better become a skewer.
우시와카!
Ushiwaka!
아무래도 각오를 해야만 할 것 같군요.
It seems that we must be prepared for the worst.
난 싫어. 난 무사시를 믿어.
I won't. I believe in Musashi.
그것도, 무사시의 동료의 우정을!
More specifically, the friendship between Musashi's friends!
-센쨩!
-우시와카 님!
-Sen-chan!
-Mr. Ushiwaka!
센쨩!
Sen-chan!
왔군, 무사시 놈.
So Musashi's here.
한조 님!
Lord Hanzo!
오, 지라이얀. 무사했구나. 역시 내 사천왕의 제일이군. 잘 됐군, 잘 됐어.
Oh, Jiraiyan, were you safe? You are truly the best of my Four Kings. Good job, good job.
뭘 화난 얼굴 하고 있나. 둘이서 무사시 놈들을 쓰러뜨리고 천하를 제패하는 것이다.
What's with your grim face? We will take those Musashi bunch down and dominate over the globe.
센짱!
Sen-chan!
-무사시!
-코지로!
-Musashi!
-Kojirō!
어떠냐, 그 쪽은.
Anything from that way?
없소.
None-dasu.
벌써 도망쳤나...
They already ran away, eh...
쉬잇! 센짱의 피리 소리이오!
Shh! I can hear Sen-chan's flute!
이쪽이오!
This way-dasu!
무사시... 코지로... 난 여기 있어.
Musashi... Kojirō... I am here.
기다리고 있었다, 무사시!
I've been waiting for you, Musashi!
한조! 센짱은 어디 있소!
Hanzo! Where is Sen-chan-dasu?!
여기까지 와 봐라. 그럼 알게 될 테다.
Come here. Then you'll know.
말 안 해도 넌 못 달아나오!
Whatever you say, you can't get away-dasu!
가라! 지라이얀!
Go! Jiraiyan!
예!
Yessir!
센히메 님!
Senhime!
코지로!
Kojirō!
믿어서 잘 됐어...
It's a good thing that I believed in you...
무사시! 센히메 님은 무사하다!
Musashi! Senhime is fine!
그걸 들으니 만사 안심이오!
Hearing that is very relieving-dasu!
한조! 어느 순간에! 멈춰라!
Hanzo! When did you escape?! Stop!
열어라, 한조!
Open the door, Hanzo!
곧 시한폭탄이 폭발한다.
A time bomb will soon explode.
뭐?!
What?!
한조 님!
Lord Hanzo!
지라이얀, 이번에야말로 저 둘을 똑바로 저 세상에 안내해라. 안녕이다.
Jiraiyan, guide them to the other world properly this time. Farewell.
젠장!
Damn!
코지로, 비키시오!
Kojirō, get out of my way-dasu!
젠장, 안 되오!
Damn, it's not working!
포기하지 마라!
Don't give up!
지라이얀!
Jiraiyan!
이제 열릴 테다!
It should open by now!
좋소, 이번엔 셋이서 스크럼이오!
Alright! We'll scrum by three this time-dasu!
좋아!
Great!
다시 한번이오!
Again-dasu!
한조! 이제 달아날 수 없을 테다! 명예롭게 할복해라!
Hanzo! There's nowhere for you to escape anymore! Disembowel and your death will be honorary!
뭔 소리냐. 이 한조 님은 불사신이다!
You must be ignorant of the fact that I, Hanzo, am immortal!
결국엔 지팡구국을 뒤엎어서 이 손에 천하를 넣겠다!
I will turn over Jipangu State and take the world into my hands!
멈춰라!
Stop!
찾았소!
We found you-dasu!
더 이상은 원하는 대로 못 할 것이오!
You won't be doing as you want anymore-dasu!
센히메 님!
Senhime!
무사시! 걱정했다!
Musashi! I've been worried for you!
네 야망도 끝이다!
Your ambition ends here!
포기해, 한조!
Give it up, Hanzo!
살아 있었군. 어떻게!
You were alive! How?!
내가 도왔다!
I helped them!
지라이얀! 잘도 배신했구나!
Jiraiyan! You betrayed me!
우린 무사시의 우정과 팀워크에 진 것이다!
We have lost to the teamwork and friendship of Musashi!
여기선 명예로이!
Save your honor!
닥쳐라! 저 배신자가! 요새와 함께 지옥에 떨어져라!
Silence, you traitor! Fall into hell with the stronghold!
안돼! 모두 도망쳐라!
No! Everyone, run away!
알겠소!
Got it-dasu!
다들 무사하오?
Are all of you okay-dasu?!
그래, 무사한 듯 하다!
Yeah, seems so!
잘 됐소!
That's great-dasu!
지라이얀! 무사했소!
Jiraiyan, you're safe-dasu!
무사시, 날 베어라!
Musashi! Cut me off!
난 악인이다. 스승을 배신했다.
I am a bad guy. I've betrayed my master.
무사 나부랭이라도 수치는 알고 있을 것이다!
Even for a fag end of swordsman, I will know my shame!
부탁한다!
Please!
지라이얀...
Jiraiyan...
케로키치!
Kerokichi!
지라이얀!
Jiraiyan!
죽는 건 멋대로겠지만 케로키치는 누가 봐 주오!
You can die whenever you want, but then what about Kerokichi-dasu?
지라이얀, 살아 있다면 계속 살아 주시오. 케로키치를 위해서라도!
Jiraiyan! You're alive, so please keep being alive! For Kerokichi, too!
날 필요로 하는 놈이 있군.
There's someone who needs me.
이걸로 됐어, 지라이얀.
That's enough, Jiraiyan.
잘 됐어.
Great.
케로키치 군을 소중히 해 줘.
Take a good care of Kerokichi.
무사시! 인사는 생략하겠다!
Musashi! I'll skip my gratitude!
딱히 인사는...
Gratitude, eh...
다만!
But!
넌 좋은 친구가 있구나.
You have good friends.
지라이얀!
Jiraiyan!
이 은혜는 언젠가 갚겠다!
I will pay back this favor!
건강하시오!
Take care-dasu!
피도 어는 카라쿠리 요새에서의 전투는 끝났다.
The blood-freezing battle at Karakuri Stronghold is over.
Something hot is gushing out from Musashi's heart, thanking the comrades who fought for the friendship despite of rivalry.
라이벌을 넘어 우정을 위해 싸운 동료에게 감사하는 무사시의 가슴에 뜨거운 무언가가 샘솟는다.
그렇지만 한조는 정말 죽고 만 것일까?
But is Hanzo truly dead?
허공의 주머니에 달이
Sometimes the moon jumps over
뛰어넘어가는 일도 있어
the pocket of empty sky
큰 소리로 웃으면
Laugh loudly and
내일에는 아침이 와
morning will come tomorrow
잃는 것 따위는 아무것도 아니야
Don't worry too much about losing
계속 해나가! 앞으로 가!
Keep going! Go for it!
맨손은 강해
A bare hand is strong
그런 거야! 가볍게 가자
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
인생 그런 거야! 기회가 어라,
That's how life is! Look, a chance
꼬리를 흔들며 쫒아와!
follows us wagging its tail!
그런 거야! 가볍게 가자
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
미래도 그런 거야! 내일이 어라,
That's how the future is, too! Look, tomorrow
양손을 벌리고 웃고 있어!
is opening its hands and smiling at us!
제너럴 이에야스의 귀국 명령으로 우리는 에도토피아에 돌아갔소.
General Ieyasu called us home, and we went back to Edotopia-dasu.
이야, 오랜만에 한가로우니 기분 좋소!
Being relaxed after a long time feels so good-dasu!
코지로는 연극 구경. 나는 제니가탄 두목하고 같이 잿날 행사.
Kojirō is watching plays, and I'm at a temple festival with Zenigatan boss.
센짱은 맞선과 함께 잠깐의 휴일을 즐기고 있더니,
Sen-chan was enjoying her marriage mettings and short holidays,
무슨! 그 한조가 살아 있었소!
What?! That Hanzo was still alive-dasu!
다음 이야기! 악이라면 제일! 한조의 부활이오
Next story! The Most Evil! Hanzo Revives
질풍노도의 에도토피아이오!
It's stormy Edotopia-dasu!
다음 이야기
악이라면 제일!
한조의 부활이오
Next Episode
The Most Evil!
Hanzo Revives
기대하세요!
Look forwards for it!